The film that cost over $20,000,000,000,000 to make.
Inside Job is a documentary, crime film directed by Charles Ferguson.
A film that exposes the shocking truth behind the economic crisis of 2008.
The global financial meltdown, at a cost of over $20 trillion,
resulted in millions of people losing their homes and jobs.
Through extensive research and interviews with major financial insiders, politicians and journalists, Inside Job traces the rise of
a rogue industry and unveils the corrosive relationships which have corrupted politics, regulation and academia.
Narrator, played by Matt Damon.
Self - Hedge Fund Manager, played by Bill Ackman.
Self - Therapist, played by Jonathan Alpert.
Self - Finance Minister, France, played by Christine Lagarde.
Self - Managing Director, Westwood Capital, played by Daniel Alpert.
Self - Special Investigative Committee, Icelandic
Parliament, played by Sigridur Benediktsdottir.
Inside Job is a 2010 American documentary film, directed by
Charles Ferguson, about the 2008 financial crisis.
Ferguson, who began researching in 2008, said the film is about "the systemic corruption of the United States by the financial services industry and the consequences of that
systemic corruption", amongst them conflicts of interest of academic research, which led to improved disclosure standards by the American Economic Association.
In five parts, the film explores how changes in the policy environment
and banking practices led to the 2008 financial crisis.
The film was acclaimed by film critics, who praised its pacing,
research, and exposition of complex material.
It was screened at the 2010 Cannes Film Festival in May 2010 and, on February 27,
2011, won Best Documentary Feature at the 83rd Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of banker, corruption, capitalism, globalization, bank.